The end is near.
Chicken Little is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Mark Dindal.
When the sky really is falling and sanity has flown the
coop, who will rise to save the day?
Together with his hysterical band of misfit friends, Chicken Little must hatch a plan to save the
planet from alien invasion and prove that the world's biggest hero is a little chicken.
Chicken Little (voice), played by Zach Braff.
Buck Cluck (voice), played by Garry Marshall.
Mayor Turkey Lurkey (voice), played by Don Knotts.
Foxy Loxy (voice), played by Amy Sedaris.
Runt of the Litter (voice), played by Steve Zahn.
Abby Mallard (voice), played by Joan Cusack.
Chicken Little is a 2005 American animated science fiction comedy
film produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
It is loosely inspired by the European folk tale "Henny Penny",
known in the United States as "Chicken Little".
Disney had previously adapted the tale in a 1943 short film.
The film follows Chicken Little who, after claiming the sky was "falling" and subsequently being ridiculed
by his town, attempts to fix his reputation, only to discover an otherworldly revelation.
The film was directed by Mark Dindal and written by Steve Bencich, Ron J.
Friedman, and Ron Anderson, and features Zach Braff as Chicken Little, with Joan Cusack, Dan Molina,
Steve Zahn, Garry Marshall, Amy Sedaris, Mark Walton, and Don Knotts in supporting roles.
Chicken Little was animated in-house at Walt Disney Feature
Animation's main headquarters in Burbank, California.
It was Disney Animation's first fully computer-animated feature film.
Chicken Little premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood on October 30, 2005, and
was released in the United States on November 4, by Walt Disney Pictures.
It was the first mainstream theatrical release in Digital 3-D, with around 100
theaters worldwide fitted with new 3-D projectors to screen the film.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $314 million,
becoming the second-highest-grossing animated film of 2005.
The film explores themes of fish, small town, space marine, superhero, chicken.
The tone is lighthearted.